<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: JEE | Ouertani Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://ouertani.github.com/blog/categories/jee/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ouertani.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-01T02:46:55+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://ouertani.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ouertani]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XML/RPC driver as JCA Scala connector]]></title>
    <link href="http://ouertani.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/xml-slash-rpc-driver-as-jca-scala-connector/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T19:41:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://ouertani.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/xml-slash-rpc-driver-as-jca-scala-connector</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Interoperability and reusability are key features of SOA architecture.</p>

<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Java_EE_Connector_Architecture">Java EE Connector architecture</a> defines a standard architecture for connecting the Java EE platform to heterogeneous EISs. This article presents an XML/RPC  adapter using a Scala JCA outbound connector to an IN/AIR legacy system.</p>

<h2>JCA and integration</h2>


<p><blockquote><p>"For enterprise application integration, bi-directional connectivity between enterprise applications and EIS is essential. The Java EE Connector architecture defines standard contracts that allow bi-directional connectivity between enterprise applications and EISs. It also formalizes the relationships, interactions, and the packaging of the integration layer, thus enabling enterprise application integration."</p></p><p><p></p><footer><strong>JCA 1.6 p 35</strong></footer></blockquote></p>

<p>The connector architecture defines a set of scalable, secure, and transactional mechanisms that enable the integration of EISs with application servers and enterprise application.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/jca.jpg" width="350" height="350" title="JCA" alt="images"></p>

<p>Using a UCIP JCA connector rather than using an <a href="http://java.dzone.com/articles/xml-rpc-using-scala">XML/RPC raw driver</a> lets you:</p>

<ol>
<li>Hide connection complexity.</li>
<li>Use connection pooling and scalability.</li>
<li>Use a standard adapter that can be deployed with any JEE 6 server from an m x n integration problem to an m + n solution</li>
</ol>


<h2>How?</h2>


<p>The use of a <a href="http://www.jcp.org/en/jsr/detail?id=322">JCA</a> resource adapter inside a JEE solution is the same as interacting with a database or queue: protocol communication and wire negotiation... are hidden to the final user.</p>

<p>Two interfaces are presented to a customer:</p>

<h3>1) A factory trait:</h3>


<p><code>scala
trait AirConnectorFactory extends Referenceable with Function0[AirConnector]
</code></p>

<h3>2) The connector trait:</h3>


<p><code>scala
trait AirConnector {
def fire(elem : Elem) : Option[Elem]
}
</code>
As an outbound communication where the resource adapter allows an ESB or EE application server to connect to an IN/AIR node and perform work. All communication is initiated by the application. The Air connector factory should be injected as any resource and used like the following.
``` scala
@Resource(name="AIR")
var airConnectorFactory : AirConnectorFactory = _</p>

<p>val output = airConnectorFactory().fire(input)
```
<blockquote><p>Source code is based on JCA 1.6 specification and hosted on <a href="https://github.com/ouertani/TelcoCX">github</a>.</p></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sending an Email using the JavaMail Session and Glassfish]]></title>
    <link href="http://ouertani.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/sending-an-email-using-the-javamail-session-and-glassfish/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T02:18:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://ouertani.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/sending-an-email-using-the-javamail-session-and-glassfish</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Purpose</h2>


<p>This tutorial is a supplement to the article of oracle published <a href="http://www.oracle.com/webfolder/technetwork/tutorials/obe/java/javamail/javamail.html">here</a>.
After reading this later, I decided to share some tips about this EE environment JavaMail api configuration.</p>

<h2>Introduction</h2>


<p>Two years ago, we decided to move to JEE 6 for our enterprise solutions and take a lot of fun with new EJB 3.1 features and annotations. Glassfish has made our lives easier, it was very easy to declare variables using it's administration console.
Less complicated than using global resource environment for properties It is also the continuation to this <a href="http://www.jroller.com/articles/jee-6-environmental-enterprise">tricks</a> this tutorial delegate to Glassfish EE server managing mail session.</p>

<h2>Prerequisites</h2>




<ol>Before starting this tutorial, you should:
<li>Fully understand of <a href="http://www.oracle.com/webfolder/technetwork/tutorials/obe/java/javamail/javamail.html">http://www.oracle.com/webfolder/technetwork/tutorials/obe/java/javamail/javamail.html</a></li>
<li>Have access to an SMTP server. You must know the host name, port number, and security settings for your SMTP server. Web mail providers may offer SMTP access, view your email account settings or help to find further information. Be aware that your user name is often your full email address and not just the name that comes before the @ symbol.</li>
<li>Have basic familiarity with Servlets and CDIs (helpful but not required)</li>
</ol>




<h2>Create a Java mail session resource :</h2>




<ol>
To create and JavaMail Session :
<li>start galssfish server</li>
<li>open admin console ( default localhost:4848)</li>
<li>Go to Resources -> JavaMail Sessions -> click new to add new javaMail resource</li>
<li>make sure the following field are filled in :</li>
</ol>


<p>Jndi name : EMailME for example, will be used later on lookup resource :
<code>java
@Resource(lookup = "EMailME")
Mail host
</code>
3-Default user
4-Default sender will be used later on mailSession.getProperty("mail.from")
5- For secure Mail add this advanced setting :</p>

<ul>
<li>mail.smtp.password : email password</li>
<li>mail.smtp.port : email port</li>
<li>mail.smtp.auth : true </li>
</ul>


<p>This screenshot summarizes all these parameters :</p>

<p><img class="center" src="/images/mailee.jpg" width="640" height="424" title="Mail EE" alt="images"></p>

<h2>II - Using email Service</h2>


<p>This tutorial is a supplement to oracle one. We will use CDI with the same example.</p>

<p>1 - MailSessionBean Will be a CDI bean with RequestScope
2- Inject the full JavaMail Session as resource rather than create it
```java
@Named
@RequestScoped
public class EmailSessionBean {</p>

<pre><code>@Resource(lookup = "EMailME")
private Session mailSession;

public void sendEmail(String to, String subject, String body) {
    MimeMessage message = new MimeMessage(mailSession);
    try {

        message.setFrom(new InternetAddress(mailSession.getProperty("mail.from")));
        InternetAddress[] address = {new InternetAddress(to)};
        message.setRecipients(Message.RecipientType.TO, address);
        message.setSubject(subject);
        message.setSentDate(new Date());
        message.setText(body);

        Transport.send(message);
    } catch (MessagingException ex) {
        ex.printStackTrace();
    }
}
</code></pre>

<p>}
```
Look short !</p>

<p>4- EmailServlet remind the same except using @Inject rather than @EJB
```java
@WebServlet(name = "EmailServlet", urlPatterns = {"/EmailServlet"})
public class EmailServlet extends HttpServlet {</p>

<pre><code>@Inject
private EmailSessionBean emailBean;

protected void processRequest(HttpServletRequest request, HttpServletResponse response)
        throws ServletException, IOException {
</code></pre>

<p> .........
   }
 ......
}
```</p>

<h2>Conclusion :</h2>


<p>Let's EE Server manager MailSession for us, keep configuration on server and thanks to Glassfish administration console managing JavaMail Session became easier.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
